Will Mowlam

Email: will@mowlam.com

Location: Worthing, UK

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/will-mowlam

GitHub: github.com/willmowlam

Portfolio: will.mowlam.com

Web consultant of 20 years for SME clients in charity and healthcare. Experience in database development, web management, content management systems, web hosting and IT support.

Frontend: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, API, Fetch/Axios, Bootstrap, Tailwind, React

Backend: Drupal, Laravel, MySQL, Node.js (npm), PHP (composer)

Tools: Git, GitHub, VSCode, Bash, Vite, Lando, Netlify, WHM, CloudLinux, Cloudflare

Relevant Experience

Web Consultant, tech-tonic.co.uk

2004 - present

- Content Management System hosting and development (Drupal, Wordpress, Joomla)
- Clients included; Thomson Scientific, NCIN, Help2Read, Action for Brazil's Children
- Hosting, maintenance and development of websites including:
 school-aid.org.za, school-aid.org, secondspring.co.uk, kolvinpsych.net, italianoliveoil.co.uk

IT Contractor, School Aid UK

2011-2020

- Lead developer working closely with staff on all major fundraising and marketing.
- Migrated and integrated a new CRM and Drupal website to improve marketing and streamline fundraising.
- Developed and maintained the Drupal website with donation and event ticketing.
- Managed all digital assets as administrator and developer, ensuring data availability, integrity and confidentiality.
- Provided technical support to senior staff, trustees and volunteers.
- Managed the digital aspect of two significant fundraising events held at Lord's Cricket Ground, including development of a Drupal auction site with SMS outbid notification.

Contract Database Developer, Thomson Scientific / Current Drugs

2004-2012

- Improved reliability of data by moving Excel workflow to relational databases with complex UI in the editorial departments at a busy drug development intelligence business.
- Provided ongoing maintenance, support and development of the databases so staff could focus on editorial work.

- Developed the technical side of an event business; sending thousands of text messages, guiding guests on unique journeys through London.
- Built event organiser and helpline software in Visual Basic plus branded event microsites.

Recent Projects

devOpps | github.com/jilloreilly/devopps | devopps.app

- Job search portal for recruiters and job seekers in software development.
- React Developer. Responsible for job search, API, CI/CD, testing and deployment.
- Tools: React, JavaScript, Tailwind, NextUI, API, Vite and Netlify.

School Aid South Africa | school-aid.org.za

- Charity website with donation facility. Promotes the charity's work and allows users to donate, give books and volunteer.
- Sole developer.
- Tools: Laravel, MySQL, Eloquent, Bootstrap, Lando, Ngrok and cPanel.

nutriSmart | github.com/willmowlam/nutriSmartApp | willmowlam.github.io/nutriSmartApp

- Single-page meal planning and nutritional tracking app that pulls data in from Edamam APIs.
- Co-developer. Built the recipe API search, favourites features and pagination.
- Tools: Bootstrap, jQuery, API and GitHub Pages.

Education

BSc (Hons) Audio and Music Technology, Anglia Ruskin University, Cambridge, UK

BTEC National Diploma in Electrical and Electronic Engineering, Richmond Upon Thames College, London, UK